var words = 
[
    {
        "question": "فَأَخَذْنَاهُمْ",
        "answer": "so We seized them",
        "pcklId": "117",
        "rootWordId": 21,
        "tlit": "fa-akhadhnāhum",
        "frequency": 273,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبُوا بِآيَاتِنَا كُلِّهَا فَأَخَذْنَاهُمْ أَخْذَ عَزِيزٍ مُقْتَدِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ذ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَخَذَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to take, to seize",
        "waznTlit": "akhadha",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 127,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَخْذَ",
        "answer": "(with) a seizure",
        "pcklId": "263",
        "rootWordId": 21,
        "tlit": "akhdha",
        "frequency": 273,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبُوا بِآيَاتِنَا كُلِّهَا فَأَخَذْنَاهُمْ أَخْذَ عَزِيزٍ مُقْتَدِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ذ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَخْذ",
        "waznEnglish": "taking, seizure",
        "waznTlit": "akhdh",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذًا",
        "answer": "then",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 28,
        "tlit": "idhan",
        "frequency": 31,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 24,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " فَقَالُوا أَبَشَرًا مِنَّا وَاحِدًا نَتَّبِعُهُ إِنَّا إِذًا لَفِي ضَلَالٍ وَسُعُرٍ",
        "rootWord": "إِذًا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِذًا",
        "waznEnglish": "then",
        "waznTlit": "idhan",
        "waznType": "Particle (Surprise particle)",
        "waznFreq": 31,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَرْضَ",
        "answer": "the earth",
        "pcklId": "411",
        "rootWordId": 32,
        "tlit": "l-arḍa",
        "frequency": 461,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 12,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَفَجَّرْنَا الْأَرْضَ عُيُونًا فَالْتَقَى الْمَاءُ عَلَىٰ أَمْرٍ قَدْ قُدِرَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ر ض",
        "waznEnglish": "the Earth, land",
        "waznTlit": "hamza rā ḍād",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 461,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَشِرٌ",
        "answer": "insolent",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 47,
        "tlit": "ashirun",
        "frequency": 2,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 25,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " أَأُلْقِيَ الذِّكْرُ عَلَيْهِ مِنْ بَيْنِنَا بَلْ هُوَ كَذَّابٌ أَشِرٌ",
        "rootWord": "أ ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ش ر",
        "waznEnglish": "insolent",
        "waznTlit": "hamza shīn rā",
        "waznType": "Adjective",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَشِرُ",
        "answer": "the insolent one",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 47,
        "tlit": "l-ashiru",
        "frequency": 2,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " سَيَعْلَمُونَ غَدًا مَنِ الْكَذَّابُ الْأَشِرُ",
        "rootWord": "أ ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ش ر",
        "waznEnglish": "insolent",
        "waznTlit": "hamza shīn rā",
        "waznType": "Adjective",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "516",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 34,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَرْسَلْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ حَاصِبًا إِلَّا آلَ لُوطٍ نَجَّيْنَاهُمْ بِسَحَرٍ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "but",
        "pcklId": "517",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 50,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا أَمْرُنَا إِلَّا وَاحِدَةٌ كَلَمْحٍ بِالْبَصَرِ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "to",
        "pcklId": "662",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": 742,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 6,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " فَتَوَلَّ عَنْهُمْ يَوْمَ يَدْعُ الدَّاعِ إِلَىٰ شَيْءٍ نُكُرٍ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition",
        "waznFreq": 742,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَى",
        "answer": "towards",
        "pcklId": "663",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": 742,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 8,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " مُهْطِعِينَ إِلَى الدَّاعِ يَقُولُ الْكَافِرُونَ هَٰذَا يَوْمٌ عَسِرٌ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition",
        "waznFreq": 742,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْ",
        "answer": "or",
        "pcklId": "118",
        "rootWordId": 66,
        "tlit": "am",
        "frequency": 137,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 43,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " أَكُفَّارُكُمْ خَيْرٌ مِنْ أُولَٰئِكُمْ أَمْ لَكُمْ بَرَاءَةٌ فِي الزُّبُرِ",
        "rootWord": "أَم",
        "rootWordType": "coordinating conjunction",
        "wazn": "أَم",
        "waznEnglish": "or",
        "waznTlit": "am",
        "waznType": "Coordinating conjunction",
        "waznFreq": 137,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْ",
        "answer": "Or",
        "pcklId": "119",
        "rootWordId": 66,
        "tlit": "am",
        "frequency": 137,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 44,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ يَقُولُونَ نَحْنُ جَمِيعٌ مُنْتَصِرٌ",
        "rootWord": "أَم",
        "rootWordType": "coordinating conjunction",
        "wazn": "أَم",
        "waznEnglish": "or",
        "waznTlit": "am",
        "waznType": "Coordinating conjunction",
        "waznFreq": 137,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْرٍ",
        "answer": "matter",
        "pcklId": "228",
        "rootWordId": 69,
        "tlit": "amrin",
        "frequency": 248,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 3,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَذَّبُوا وَاتَّبَعُوا أَهْوَاءَهُمْ وَكُلُّ أَمْرٍ مُسْتَقِرٌّ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمْر",
        "waznEnglish": "command, affair, matter",
        "waznTlit": "amr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 166,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْرٍ",
        "answer": "a matter",
        "pcklId": "229",
        "rootWordId": 69,
        "tlit": "amrin",
        "frequency": 248,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 12,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَفَجَّرْنَا الْأَرْضَ عُيُونًا فَالْتَقَى الْمَاءُ عَلَىٰ أَمْرٍ قَدْ قُدِرَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمْر",
        "waznEnglish": "command, affair, matter",
        "waznTlit": "amr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 166,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْرُنَا",
        "answer": "(is) Our Command",
        "pcklId": "230",
        "rootWordId": 69,
        "tlit": "amrunā",
        "frequency": 248,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 50,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا أَمْرُنَا إِلَّا وَاحِدَةٌ كَلَمْحٍ بِالْبَصَرِ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمْر",
        "waznEnglish": "command, affair, matter",
        "waznTlit": "amr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 166,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "آلَ",
        "answer": "(the) family",
        "pcklId": "151",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "āla",
        "frequency": 170,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 34,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَرْسَلْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ حَاصِبًا إِلَّا آلَ لُوطٍ نَجَّيْنَاهُمْ بِسَحَرٍ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ءَال",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "āl",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 26,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "آلَ",
        "answer": "(to the) people",
        "pcklId": "152",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "āla",
        "frequency": 170,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 41,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ جَاءَ آلَ فِرْعَوْنَ النُّذُرُ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ءَال",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "āl",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 26,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "آيَةً",
        "answer": "a Sign",
        "pcklId": "365",
        "rootWordId": 90,
        "tlit": "āyatan",
        "frequency": 382,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 2,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ يَرَوْا آيَةً يُعْرِضُوا وَيَقُولُوا سِحْرٌ مُسْتَمِرٌّ",
        "rootWord": "أ ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ي ي",
        "waznEnglish": "Our Signs",
        "waznTlit": "hamza yā yā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 382,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "آيَةً",
        "answer": "(as) a Sign",
        "pcklId": "366",
        "rootWordId": 90,
        "tlit": "āyatan",
        "frequency": 382,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 15,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ تَرَكْنَاهَا آيَةً فَهَلْ مِنْ مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "أ ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ي ي",
        "waznEnglish": "Our Signs",
        "waznTlit": "hamza yā yā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 382,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِآيَاتِنَا",
        "answer": "Our Signs",
        "pcklId": "367",
        "rootWordId": 90,
        "tlit": "biāyātinā",
        "frequency": 382,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبُوا بِآيَاتِنَا كُلِّهَا فَأَخَذْنَاهُمْ أَخْذَ عَزِيزٍ مُقْتَدِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "أ ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ي ي",
        "waznEnglish": "Our Signs",
        "waznTlit": "hamza yā yā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 382,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بَرَاءَةٌ",
        "answer": "(is) an exemption",
        "pcklId": "12",
        "rootWordId": 110,
        "tlit": "barāatun",
        "frequency": 31,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 43,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " أَكُفَّارُكُمْ خَيْرٌ مِنْ أُولَٰئِكُمْ أَمْ لَكُمْ بَرَاءَةٌ فِي الزُّبُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ب ر أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَرَآءَة",
        "waznEnglish": "We bring it into existence",
        "waznTlit": "barāat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَبَشَرًا",
        "answer": "Is (it) a human being",
        "pcklId": "82",
        "rootWordId": 128,
        "tlit": "abasharan",
        "frequency": 123,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 24,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَقَالُوا أَبَشَرًا مِنَّا وَاحِدًا نَتَّبِعُهُ إِنَّا إِذًا لَفِي ضَلَالٍ وَسُعُرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ب ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَشَر",
        "waznEnglish": "And give good news",
        "waznTlit": "bashar",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 37,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَبْصَارُهُمْ",
        "answer": "their eyes",
        "pcklId": "69",
        "rootWordId": 129,
        "tlit": "abṣāruhum",
        "frequency": 148,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " خُشَّعًا أَبْصَارُهُمْ يَخْرُجُونَ مِنَ الْأَجْدَاثِ كَأَنَّهُمْ جَرَادٌ مُنْتَشِرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ب ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَصَر",
        "waznEnglish": "I perceived",
        "waznTlit": "baṣar",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 48,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالْبَصَرِ",
        "answer": "(of) the eye",
        "pcklId": "70",
        "rootWordId": 129,
        "tlit": "bil-baṣari",
        "frequency": 148,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 50,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا أَمْرُنَا إِلَّا وَاحِدَةٌ كَلَمْحٍ بِالْبَصَرِ",
        "rootWord": "ب ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَصَر",
        "waznEnglish": "I perceived",
        "waznTlit": "baṣar",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 48,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بَطْشَتَنَا",
        "answer": "(of) Our seizure",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 134,
        "tlit": "baṭshatanā",
        "frequency": 10,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 36,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ أَنْذَرَهُمْ بَطْشَتَنَا فَتَمَارَوْا بِالنُّذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ب ط ش",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَطْشَة",
        "waznEnglish": "(to) hold",
        "waznTlit": "baṭshat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بُكْرَةً",
        "answer": "early",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 151,
        "tlit": "buk'ratan",
        "frequency": 12,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 38,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ صَبَّحَهُمْ بُكْرَةً عَذَابٌ مُسْتَقِرٌّ",
        "rootWord": "ب ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بُكْرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "and (in) the morning",
        "waznTlit": "buk'rat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 7,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بَالِغَةٌ",
        "answer": "perfect",
        "pcklId": "76",
        "rootWordId": 157,
        "tlit": "bālighatun",
        "frequency": 77,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 5,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " حِكْمَةٌ بَالِغَةٌ فَمَا تُغْنِ النُّذُرُ",
        "rootWord": "ب ل غ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَٰلِغَة",
        "waznEnglish": "reaches",
        "waznTlit": "bālighat",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَبْوَابَ",
        "answer": "(the) gates",
        "pcklId": "24",
        "rootWordId": 166,
        "tlit": "abwāba",
        "frequency": 27,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 11,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَفَتَحْنَا أَبْوَابَ السَّمَاءِ بِمَاءٍ مُنْهَمِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ب و ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ب و ب",
        "waznEnglish": "the gate",
        "waznTlit": "bā wāw bā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 27,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بَيْنَهُمْ",
        "answer": "between them",
        "pcklId": "278",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "baynahum",
        "frequency": 523,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَبِّئْهُمْ أَنَّ الْمَاءَ قِسْمَةٌ بَيْنَهُمْ كُلُّ شِرْبٍ مُحْتَضَرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَيْن",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "bayn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)",
        "waznFreq": 266,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بَيْنِنَا",
        "answer": "among us",
        "pcklId": "322",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "bayninā",
        "frequency": 523,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 25,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " أَأُلْقِيَ الذِّكْرُ عَلَيْهِ مِنْ بَيْنِنَا بَلْ هُوَ كَذَّابٌ أَشِرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَيْن",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "bayn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 266,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاتَّبَعُوا",
        "answer": "and followed",
        "pcklId": "155",
        "rootWordId": 176,
        "tlit": "wa-ittabaʿū",
        "frequency": 172,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 3,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَذَّبُوا وَاتَّبَعُوا أَهْوَاءَهُمْ وَكُلُّ أَمْرٍ مُسْتَقِرٌّ",
        "rootWord": "ت ب ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱتَّبَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to follow",
        "waznTlit": "ittabaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 136,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نَتَّبِعُهُ",
        "answer": "(that) we should follow him",
        "pcklId": "156",
        "rootWordId": 176,
        "tlit": "nattabiʿuhu",
        "frequency": 172,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 24,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " فَقَالُوا أَبَشَرًا مِنَّا وَاحِدًا نَتَّبِعُهُ إِنَّا إِذًا لَفِي ضَلَالٍ وَسُعُرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ت ب ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱتَّبَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to follow",
        "waznTlit": "ittabaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 136,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَرَكْنَاهَا",
        "answer": "We left it",
        "pcklId": "36",
        "rootWordId": 182,
        "tlit": "taraknāhā",
        "frequency": 43,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 15,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ تَرَكْنَاهَا آيَةً فَهَلْ مِنْ مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ت ر ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَرَكَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to leave",
        "waznTlit": "taraka",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 40,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَجْدَاثِ",
        "answer": "the graves",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 228,
        "tlit": "l-ajdāthi",
        "frequency": 3,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " خُشَّعًا أَبْصَارُهُمْ يَخْرُجُونَ مِنَ الْأَجْدَاثِ كَأَنَّهُمْ جَرَادٌ مُنْتَشِرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ج د ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج د ث",
        "waznEnglish": "the graves",
        "waznTlit": "jīm dāl thā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "جَرَادٌ",
        "answer": "locusts",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 236,
        "tlit": "jarādun",
        "frequency": 2,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " خُشَّعًا أَبْصَارُهُمْ يَخْرُجُونَ مِنَ الْأَجْدَاثِ كَأَنَّهُمْ جَرَادٌ مُنْتَشِرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ج ر د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ر د",
        "waznEnglish": "and the locusts",
        "waznTlit": "jīm rā dāl",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُجْرِمِينَ",
        "answer": "the criminals",
        "pcklId": "50",
        "rootWordId": 241,
        "tlit": "l-muj'rimīna",
        "frequency": 66,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 47,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْمُجْرِمِينَ فِي ضَلَالٍ وَسُعُرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ج ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُجْرِم",
        "waznEnglish": "incite you",
        "waznTlit": "muj'rim",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 52,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَجْرِي",
        "answer": "Sailing",
        "pcklId": "47",
        "rootWordId": 242,
        "tlit": "tajrī",
        "frequency": 64,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 14,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " تَجْرِي بِأَعْيُنِنَا",
        "rootWord": "ج ر ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَرَيْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to flow, to run",
        "waznTlit": "jaray",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 57,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نَجْزِي",
        "answer": "We reward",
        "pcklId": "68",
        "rootWordId": 245,
        "tlit": "najzī",
        "frequency": 118,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 35,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " نِعْمَةً مِنْ عِنْدِنَا كَذَٰلِكَ نَجْزِي مَنْ شَكَرَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ز ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَزَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to reward, to recompense",
        "waznTlit": "jazā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 73,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "جَزَاءً",
        "answer": "a reward",
        "pcklId": "107",
        "rootWordId": 245,
        "tlit": "jazāan",
        "frequency": 118,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 14,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " تَجْرِي بِأَعْيُنِنَا جَزَاءً لِمَنْ كَانَ كُفِرَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ز ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَزَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "avail",
        "waznTlit": "jazā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 42,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجَمْعُ",
        "answer": "(their) assembly",
        "pcklId": "63",
        "rootWordId": 260,
        "tlit": "l-jamʿu",
        "frequency": 129,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 45,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " سَيُهْزَمُ الْجَمْعُ وَيُوَلُّونَ الدُّبُرَ",
        "rootWord": "ج م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَمْع",
        "waznEnglish": "We will gather them",
        "waznTlit": "jamʿ",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 13,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "جَمِيعٌ",
        "answer": "(are) an assembly",
        "pcklId": "115",
        "rootWordId": 260,
        "tlit": "jamīʿun",
        "frequency": 129,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 44,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ يَقُولُونَ نَحْنُ جَمِيعٌ مُنْتَصِرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ج م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَمِيع",
        "waznEnglish": "We will gather them",
        "waznTlit": "jamīʿ",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 53,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "جَنَّاتٍ",
        "answer": "gardens",
        "pcklId": "103",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "jannātin",
        "frequency": 201,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 54,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْمُتَّقِينَ فِي جَنَّاتٍ وَنَهَرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَنَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "jannat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 147,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَجْنُونٌ",
        "answer": "A madman",
        "pcklId": "197",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "majnūnun",
        "frequency": 201,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 9,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبَتْ قَبْلَهُمْ قَوْمُ نُوحٍ فَكَذَّبُوا عَبْدَنَا وَقَالُوا مَجْنُونٌ وَازْدُجِرَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَجْنُون",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "majnūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle",
        "waznFreq": 11,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "جَاءَهُمْ",
        "answer": "has come to them",
        "pcklId": "256",
        "rootWordId": 281,
        "tlit": "jāahum",
        "frequency": 278,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 4,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ جَاءَهُمْ مِنَ الْأَنْبَاءِ مَا فِيهِ مُزْدَجَرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ج ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ي أ",
        "waznEnglish": "to come",
        "waznTlit": "jīm yā hamza",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 278,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "جَاءَ",
        "answer": "came",
        "pcklId": "257",
        "rootWordId": 281,
        "tlit": "jāa",
        "frequency": 278,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 41,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ جَاءَ آلَ فِرْعَوْنَ النُّذُرُ",
        "rootWord": "ج ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ي أ",
        "waznEnglish": "to come",
        "waznTlit": "jīm yā hamza",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 278,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "حَاصِبًا",
        "answer": "a storm of stones",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 323,
        "tlit": "ḥāṣiban",
        "frequency": 5,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 34,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَرْسَلْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ حَاصِبًا إِلَّا آلَ لُوطٍ نَجَّيْنَاهُمْ بِسَحَرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ح ص ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَاصِب",
        "waznEnglish": "(are) firewood",
        "waznTlit": "ḥāṣib",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُحْتَضَرٌ",
        "answer": "attended",
        "pcklId": "24",
        "rootWordId": 330,
        "tlit": "muḥ'taḍarun",
        "frequency": 25,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَبِّئْهُمْ أَنَّ الْمَاءَ قِسْمَةٌ بَيْنَهُمْ كُلُّ شِرْبٍ مُحْتَضَرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ح ض ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّحْتَضَر",
        "waznEnglish": "came to",
        "waznTlit": "muḥ'taḍar",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُحْتَظِرِ",
        "answer": "(used by) a fence builder",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 335,
        "tlit": "l-muḥ'taẓiri",
        "frequency": 2,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَرْسَلْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ صَيْحَةً وَاحِدَةً فَكَانُوا كَهَشِيمِ الْمُحْتَظِرِ",
        "rootWord": "ح ظ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُحْتَظِر",
        "waznEnglish": "restricted",
        "waznTlit": "muḥ'taẓir",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "حِكْمَةٌ",
        "answer": "Wisdom",
        "pcklId": "103",
        "rootWordId": 345,
        "tlit": "ḥik'matun",
        "frequency": 210,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 5,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " حِكْمَةٌ بَالِغَةٌ فَمَا تُغْنِ النُّذُرُ",
        "rootWord": "ح ك م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حِكْمَة",
        "waznEnglish": "will judge",
        "waznTlit": "ḥik'mat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 20,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَحَمَلْنَاهُ",
        "answer": "And We carried him",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 354,
        "tlit": "waḥamalnāhu",
        "frequency": 64,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 13,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَحَمَلْنَاهُ عَلَىٰ ذَاتِ أَلْوَاحٍ وَدُسُرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ح م ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَمَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to carry, to bear",
        "waznTlit": "ḥamala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 41,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَخْرُجُونَ",
        "answer": "they will come forth",
        "pcklId": "43",
        "rootWordId": 397,
        "tlit": "yakhrujūna",
        "frequency": 182,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " خُشَّعًا أَبْصَارُهُمْ يَخْرُجُونَ مِنَ الْأَجْدَاثِ",
        "rootWord": "خ ر ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَرَجَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to go out, to come out, to depart, to leave",
        "waznTlit": "kharaja",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 53,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "خُشَّعًا",
        "answer": "(Will be) humbled",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 409,
        "tlit": "khushaʿan",
        "frequency": 17,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " خُشَّعًا أَبْصَارُهُمْ يَخْرُجُونَ مِنَ الْأَجْدَاثِ كَأَنَّهُمْ جَرَادٌ مُنْتَشِرٌ",
        "rootWord": "خ ش ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَاشِع",
        "waznEnglish": "And (will be) humbled",
        "waznTlit": "khāshiʿ",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 14,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَقْنَاهُ",
        "answer": "We created it",
        "pcklId": "147",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalaqnāhu",
        "frequency": 261,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 49,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا كُلَّ شَيْءٍ خَلَقْنَاهُ بِقَدَرٍ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 184,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "خَيْرٌ",
        "answer": "better",
        "pcklId": "182",
        "rootWordId": 449,
        "tlit": "khayrun",
        "frequency": 196,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 43,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " أَكُفَّارُكُمْ خَيْرٌ مِنْ أُولَٰئِكُمْ أَمْ لَكُمْ بَرَاءَةٌ فِي الزُّبُرِ",
        "rootWord": "خ ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَيْر",
        "waznEnglish": "they select",
        "waznTlit": "khayr",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 178,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الدُّبُرَ",
        "answer": "(their) backs",
        "pcklId": "32",
        "rootWordId": 455,
        "tlit": "l-dubura",
        "frequency": 44,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 45,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " سَيُهْزَمُ الْجَمْعُ وَيُوَلُّونَ الدُّبُرَ",
        "rootWord": "د ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دُبُر",
        "waznEnglish": "disposing",
        "waznTlit": "dubur",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 18,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَدُسُرٍ",
        "answer": "and nails",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 470,
        "tlit": "wadusurin",
        "frequency": 1,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 13,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَحَمَلْنَاهُ عَلَىٰ ذَاتِ أَلْوَاحٍ وَدُسُرٍ",
        "rootWord": "د س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "د س ر",
        "waznEnglish": "and nails",
        "waznTlit": "dāl sīn rā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَدْعُ",
        "answer": "will call",
        "pcklId": "154",
        "rootWordId": 474,
        "tlit": "yadʿu",
        "frequency": 212,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 6,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " فَتَوَلَّ عَنْهُمْ يَوْمَ يَدْعُ الدَّاعِ إِلَىٰ شَيْءٍ نُكُرٍ",
        "rootWord": "د ع و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دَعَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to call, to invite, to pray",
        "waznTlit": "daʿā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 170,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَدَعَا",
        "answer": "So he called",
        "pcklId": "155",
        "rootWordId": 474,
        "tlit": "fadaʿā",
        "frequency": 212,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 10,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَدَعَا رَبَّهُ أَنِّي مَغْلُوبٌ فَانْتَصِرْ",
        "rootWord": "د ع و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دَعَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to call, to invite, to pray",
        "waznTlit": "daʿā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 170,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الدَّاعِ",
        "answer": "the caller",
        "pcklId": "206",
        "rootWordId": 474,
        "tlit": "l-dāʿi",
        "frequency": 212,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 6,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " فَتَوَلَّ عَنْهُمْ يَوْمَ يَدْعُ الدَّاعِ إِلَىٰ شَيْءٍ نُكُرٍ",
        "rootWord": "د ع و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دَّاع",
        "waznEnglish": "and call",
        "waznTlit": "dāʿ",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الدَّاعِ",
        "answer": "the caller",
        "pcklId": "207",
        "rootWordId": 474,
        "tlit": "l-dāʿi",
        "frequency": 212,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 8,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " مُهْطِعِينَ إِلَى الدَّاعِ يَقُولُ الْكَافِرُونَ هَٰذَا يَوْمٌ عَسِرٌ",
        "rootWord": "د ع و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دَّاع",
        "waznEnglish": "and call",
        "waznTlit": "dāʿ",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَدْهَىٰ",
        "answer": "(will be) more grievous",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 493,
        "tlit": "adhā",
        "frequency": 1,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 46,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " بَلِ السَّاعَةُ مَوْعِدُهُمْ وَالسَّاعَةُ أَدْهَىٰ وَأَمَرُّ",
        "rootWord": "د ه ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "د ه ي",
        "waznEnglish": "(will be) more grievous",
        "waznTlit": "dāl hā yā",
        "waznType": "Adjective",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلذِّكْرِ",
        "answer": "for remembrance",
        "pcklId": "256",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "lildhik'ri",
        "frequency": 292,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 17,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ يَسَّرْنَا الْقُرْآنَ لِلذِّكْرِ فَهَلْ مِنْ مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذِكْر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhik'r",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun",
        "waznFreq": 76,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلذِّكْرِ",
        "answer": "for remembrance",
        "pcklId": "257",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "lildhik'ri",
        "frequency": 292,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 22,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ يَسَّرْنَا الْقُرْآنَ لِلذِّكْرِ فَهَلْ مِنْ مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذِكْر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhik'r",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun",
        "waznFreq": 76,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الذِّكْرُ",
        "answer": "the Reminder",
        "pcklId": "258",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "l-dhik'ru",
        "frequency": 292,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 25,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " أَأُلْقِيَ الذِّكْرُ عَلَيْهِ مِنْ بَيْنِنَا بَلْ هُوَ كَذَّابٌ أَشِرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذِكْر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhik'r",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun",
        "waznFreq": 76,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلذِّكْرِ",
        "answer": "for remembrance",
        "pcklId": "259",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "lildhik'ri",
        "frequency": 292,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ يَسَّرْنَا الْقُرْآنَ لِلذِّكْرِ فَهَلْ مِنْ مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذِكْر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhik'r",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun",
        "waznFreq": 76,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلذِّكْرِ",
        "answer": "for remembrance",
        "pcklId": "260",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "lildhik'ri",
        "frequency": 292,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 40,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ يَسَّرْنَا الْقُرْآنَ لِلذِّكْرِ فَهَلْ مِنْ مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذِكْر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhik'r",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun",
        "waznFreq": 76,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "answer": "who will receive admonition",
        "pcklId": "286",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "muddakirin",
        "frequency": 292,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 15,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ تَرَكْنَاهَا آيَةً فَهَلْ مِنْ مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّدَّكِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "muddakir",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "answer": "who will receive admonition",
        "pcklId": "287",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "muddakirin",
        "frequency": 292,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 17,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ يَسَّرْنَا الْقُرْآنَ لِلذِّكْرِ فَهَلْ مِنْ مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّدَّكِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "muddakir",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "answer": "who will receive admonition",
        "pcklId": "288",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "muddakirin",
        "frequency": 292,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 22,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ يَسَّرْنَا الْقُرْآنَ لِلذِّكْرِ فَهَلْ مِنْ مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّدَّكِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "muddakir",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "answer": "who will receive admonition",
        "pcklId": "289",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "muddakirin",
        "frequency": 292,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ يَسَّرْنَا الْقُرْآنَ لِلذِّكْرِ فَهَلْ مِنْ مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّدَّكِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "muddakir",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "answer": "who will receive admonition",
        "pcklId": "290",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "muddakirin",
        "frequency": 292,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 40,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ يَسَّرْنَا الْقُرْآنَ لِلذِّكْرِ فَهَلْ مِنْ مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّدَّكِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "muddakir",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "answer": "who will receive admonition",
        "pcklId": "291",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "muddakirin",
        "frequency": 292,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 51,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ أَهْلَكْنَا أَشْيَاعَكُمْ فَهَلْ مِنْ مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّدَّكِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "muddakir",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَذُوقُوا",
        "answer": "So taste",
        "pcklId": "28",
        "rootWordId": 519,
        "tlit": "fadhūqū",
        "frequency": 63,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 37,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ رَاوَدُوهُ عَنْ ضَيْفِهِ فَطَمَسْنَا أَعْيُنَهُمْ فَذُوقُوا عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ذ و ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذَاقُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to taste",
        "waznTlit": "dhāqu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 36,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَذُوقُوا",
        "answer": "So taste",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 519,
        "tlit": "fadhūqū",
        "frequency": 63,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 39,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَذُوقُوا عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ذ و ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذَاقُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to taste",
        "waznTlit": "dhāqu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 36,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "ذُوقُوا",
        "answer": "Taste",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 519,
        "tlit": "dhūqū",
        "frequency": 63,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 48,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يُسْحَبُونَ فِي النَّارِ عَلَىٰ وُجُوهِهِمْ ذُوقُوا مَسَّ سَقَرَ",
        "rootWord": "ذ و ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذَاقُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to taste",
        "waznTlit": "dhāqu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 36,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَرَوْا",
        "answer": "they see",
        "pcklId": "220",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "yaraw",
        "frequency": 328,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 2,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ يَرَوْا آيَةً يُعْرِضُوا وَيَقُولُوا سِحْرٌ مُسْتَمِرٌّ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 271,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبَّهُ",
        "answer": "his Lord",
        "pcklId": "821",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbahu",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 10,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَدَعَا رَبَّهُ أَنِّي مَغْلُوبٌ فَانْتَصِرْ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَرْسَلْنَا",
        "answer": "[We] sent",
        "pcklId": "116",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "arsalnā",
        "frequency": 513,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 19,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَرْسَلْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ رِيحًا صَرْصَرًا فِي يَوْمِ نَحْسٍ مُسْتَمِرٍّ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَرْسَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to send",
        "waznTlit": "arsala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 130,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَرْسَلْنَا",
        "answer": "[We] sent",
        "pcklId": "117",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "arsalnā",
        "frequency": 513,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَرْسَلْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ صَيْحَةً وَاحِدَةً فَكَانُوا كَهَشِيمِ الْمُحْتَظِرِ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَرْسَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to send",
        "waznTlit": "arsala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 130,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَرْسَلْنَا",
        "answer": "[We] sent",
        "pcklId": "118",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "arsalnā",
        "frequency": 513,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 34,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَرْسَلْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ حَاصِبًا إِلَّا آلَ لُوطٍ نَجَّيْنَاهُمْ بِسَحَرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَرْسَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to send",
        "waznTlit": "arsala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 130,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُرْسِلُو",
        "answer": "(are) sending",
        "pcklId": "475",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "mur'silū",
        "frequency": 513,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 27,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا مُرْسِلُو النَّاقَةِ فِتْنَةً لَهُمْ فَارْتَقِبْهُمْ وَاصْطَبِرْ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُرْسِل",
        "waznEnglish": "[We] have sent you",
        "waznTlit": "mur'sil",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَارْتَقِبْهُمْ",
        "answer": "so watch them",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 575,
        "tlit": "fa-ir'taqib'hum",
        "frequency": 24,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 27,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا مُرْسِلُو النَّاقَةِ فِتْنَةً لَهُمْ فَارْتَقِبْهُمْ وَاصْطَبِرْ",
        "rootWord": "ر ق ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱرْتَقِبْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to watch",
        "waznTlit": "ir'taqib",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رِيحًا",
        "answer": "a wind",
        "pcklId": "53",
        "rootWordId": 599,
        "tlit": "rīḥan",
        "frequency": 57,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 19,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَرْسَلْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ رِيحًا صَرْصَرًا فِي يَوْمِ نَحْسٍ مُسْتَمِرٍّ",
        "rootWord": "ر و ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رِيح",
        "waznEnglish": "you bring them in",
        "waznTlit": "rīḥ",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 29,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَاوَدُوهُ",
        "answer": "they demanded from him",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 600,
        "tlit": "rāwadūhu",
        "frequency": 148,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 37,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ رَاوَدُوهُ عَنْ ضَيْفِهِ فَطَمَسْنَا أَعْيُنَهُمْ",
        "rootWord": "ر و د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَٰوَدُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to seduce, to demand, to get permission",
        "waznTlit": "rāwadu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form III)",
        "waznFreq": 8,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الزُّبُرِ",
        "answer": "the Scriptures",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 609,
        "tlit": "l-zuburi",
        "frequency": 11,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 43,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " أَكُفَّارُكُمْ خَيْرٌ مِنْ أُولَٰئِكُمْ أَمْ لَكُمْ بَرَاءَةٌ فِي الزُّبُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ز ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زُبُر",
        "waznEnglish": "sheets",
        "waznTlit": "zubur",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 7,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الزُّبُرِ",
        "answer": "the written records",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 609,
        "tlit": "l-zuburi",
        "frequency": 11,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 52,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكُلُّ شَيْءٍ فَعَلُوهُ فِي الزُّبُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ز ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زُبُر",
        "waznEnglish": "sheets",
        "waznTlit": "zubur",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 7,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَازْدُجِرَ",
        "answer": "and he was repelled",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 612,
        "tlit": "wa-uz'dujira",
        "frequency": 6,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 9,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَذَّبُوا عَبْدَنَا وَقَالُوا مَجْنُونٌ وَازْدُجِرَ",
        "rootWord": "ز ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱزْدُجِرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to repell",
        "waznTlit": "uz'dujira",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُزْدَجَرٌ",
        "answer": "(is) deterrence",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 612,
        "tlit": "muz'dajarun",
        "frequency": 6,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 4,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ جَاءَهُمْ مِنَ الْأَنْبَاءِ مَا فِيهِ مُزْدَجَرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ز ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُزْدَجَر",
        "waznEnglish": "and he was repelled",
        "waznTlit": "muz'dajar",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يُسْحَبُونَ",
        "answer": "they will be dragged",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 664,
        "tlit": "yus'ḥabūna",
        "frequency": 11,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 48,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يُسْحَبُونَ فِي النَّارِ عَلَىٰ وُجُوهِهِمْ ذُوقُوا مَسَّ سَقَرَ",
        "rootWord": "س ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يُسْحَبُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to drag",
        "waznTlit": "yus'ḥabu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِسَحَرٍ",
        "answer": "by dawn",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 666,
        "tlit": "bisaḥarin",
        "frequency": 63,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 34,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَرْسَلْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ حَاصِبًا إِلَّا آلَ لُوطٍ نَجَّيْنَاهُمْ بِسَحَرٍ",
        "rootWord": "س ح ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَحَر",
        "waznEnglish": "they bewitched",
        "waznTlit": "saḥar",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سِحْرٌ",
        "answer": "Magic",
        "pcklId": "32",
        "rootWordId": 666,
        "tlit": "siḥ'run",
        "frequency": 63,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 2,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ يَرَوْا آيَةً يُعْرِضُوا وَيَقُولُوا سِحْرٌ مُسْتَمِرٌّ",
        "rootWord": "س ح ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سِحْر",
        "waznEnglish": "they bewitched",
        "waznTlit": "siḥ'r",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 28,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُسْتَطَرٌ",
        "answer": "(is) written down",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 688,
        "tlit": "mus'taṭarun",
        "frequency": 16,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 53,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكُلُّ صَغِيرٍ وَكَبِيرٍ مُسْتَطَرٌ",
        "rootWord": "س ط ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّسْتَطَر",
        "waznEnglish": "they write",
        "waznTlit": "mus'taṭar",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَسُعُرٍ",
        "answer": "and madness",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 691,
        "tlit": "wasuʿurin",
        "frequency": 19,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 24,
        "wordnum": 10,
        "arabicAyah": " فَقَالُوا أَبَشَرًا مِنَّا وَاحِدًا نَتَّبِعُهُ إِنَّا إِذًا لَفِي ضَلَالٍ وَسُعُرٍ",
        "rootWord": "س ع ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سُعُر",
        "waznEnglish": "is set ablaze",
        "waznTlit": "suʿur",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَسُعُرٍ",
        "answer": "and madness",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 691,
        "tlit": "wasuʿurin",
        "frequency": 19,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 47,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْمُجْرِمِينَ فِي ضَلَالٍ وَسُعُرٍ",
        "rootWord": "س ع ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سُعُر",
        "waznEnglish": "is set ablaze",
        "waznTlit": "suʿur",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّمَاءِ",
        "answer": "(of) heaven",
        "pcklId": "312",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "l-samāi",
        "frequency": 381,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 11,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَفَتَحْنَا أَبْوَابَ السَّمَاءِ بِمَاءٍ مُنْهَمِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "samā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 310,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّاعَةُ",
        "answer": "the Hour",
        "pcklId": "43",
        "rootWordId": 742,
        "tlit": "l-sāʿatu",
        "frequency": 49,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 1,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " اقْتَرَبَتِ السَّاعَةُ وَانْشَقَّ الْقَمَرُ",
        "rootWord": "س و ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَاعَة",
        "waznEnglish": "the Hour",
        "waznTlit": "sāʿat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 48,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّاعَةُ",
        "answer": "the Hour",
        "pcklId": "44",
        "rootWordId": 742,
        "tlit": "l-sāʿatu",
        "frequency": 49,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 46,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " بَلِ السَّاعَةُ مَوْعِدُهُمْ",
        "rootWord": "س و ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَاعَة",
        "waznEnglish": "the Hour",
        "waznTlit": "sāʿat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 48,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالسَّاعَةُ",
        "answer": "and the Hour",
        "pcklId": "45",
        "rootWordId": 742,
        "tlit": "wal-sāʿatu",
        "frequency": 49,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 46,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَالسَّاعَةُ أَدْهَىٰ وَأَمَرُّ",
        "rootWord": "س و ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَاعَة",
        "waznEnglish": "the Hour",
        "waznTlit": "sāʿat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 48,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "شِرْبٍ",
        "answer": "drink",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 763,
        "tlit": "shir'bin",
        "frequency": 39,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَبِّئْهُمْ أَنَّ الْمَاءَ قِسْمَةٌ بَيْنَهُمْ كُلُّ شِرْبٍ مُحْتَضَرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ش ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شِرْب",
        "waznEnglish": "and drink",
        "waznTlit": "shir'b",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَانْشَقَّ",
        "answer": "and has split",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 787,
        "tlit": "wa-inshaqqa",
        "frequency": 28,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 1,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " اقْتَرَبَتِ السَّاعَةُ وَانْشَقَّ الْقَمَرُ",
        "rootWord": "ش ق ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱنشَقَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to split",
        "waznTlit": "inshaqqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VII)",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "شَكَرَ",
        "answer": "(is) grateful",
        "pcklId": "43",
        "rootWordId": 789,
        "tlit": "shakara",
        "frequency": 75,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 35,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " نِعْمَةً مِنْ عِنْدِنَا كَذَٰلِكَ نَجْزِي مَنْ شَكَرَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَكَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be grateful, to give thanks",
        "waznTlit": "shakara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 46,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "شَيْءٍ",
        "answer": "a thing",
        "pcklId": "488",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "shayin",
        "frequency": 519,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 6,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " فَتَوَلَّ عَنْهُمْ يَوْمَ يَدْعُ الدَّاعِ إِلَىٰ شَيْءٍ نُكُرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَىْء",
        "waznEnglish": "had willed",
        "waznTlit": "shay",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 283,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "شَيْءٍ",
        "answer": "thing",
        "pcklId": "489",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "shayin",
        "frequency": 519,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 49,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا كُلَّ شَيْءٍ خَلَقْنَاهُ بِقَدَرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَىْء",
        "waznEnglish": "had willed",
        "waznTlit": "shay",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 283,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "شَيْءٍ",
        "answer": "thing",
        "pcklId": "490",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "shayin",
        "frequency": 519,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 52,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكُلُّ شَيْءٍ فَعَلُوهُ فِي الزُّبُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَىْء",
        "waznEnglish": "had willed",
        "waznTlit": "shay",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 283,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَشْيَاعَكُمْ",
        "answer": "your kinds",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 814,
        "tlit": "ashyāʿakum",
        "frequency": 12,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 51,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ أَهْلَكْنَا أَشْيَاعَكُمْ فَهَلْ مِنْ مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شِيعَة",
        "waznEnglish": "(should) spread",
        "waznTlit": "shīʿat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 11,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "صَبَّحَهُمْ",
        "answer": "seized them in the morning",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 817,
        "tlit": "ṣabbaḥahum",
        "frequency": 45,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 38,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ صَبَّحَهُمْ بُكْرَةً عَذَابٌ مُسْتَقِرٌّ",
        "rootWord": "ص ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَبَّحَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to seize in the morning",
        "waznTlit": "ṣabbaḥa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاصْطَبِرْ",
        "answer": "and be patient",
        "pcklId": "61",
        "rootWordId": 818,
        "tlit": "wa-iṣ'ṭabir",
        "frequency": 103,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 27,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا مُرْسِلُو النَّاقَةِ فِتْنَةً لَهُمْ فَارْتَقِبْهُمْ وَاصْطَبِرْ",
        "rootWord": "ص ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱصْطَبِرْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be patient, to be steadfast",
        "waznTlit": "iṣ'ṭabir",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "صَاحِبَهُمْ",
        "answer": "their companion",
        "pcklId": "88",
        "rootWordId": 822,
        "tlit": "ṣāḥibahum",
        "frequency": 97,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 29,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَنَادَوْا صَاحِبَهُمْ فَتَعَاطَىٰ فَعَقَرَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَاحِب",
        "waznEnglish": "can be protected",
        "waznTlit": "ṣāḥib",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 10,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "صِدْقٍ",
        "answer": "(of) honor",
        "pcklId": "46",
        "rootWordId": 830,
        "tlit": "ṣid'qin",
        "frequency": 155,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 55,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فِي مَقْعَدِ صِدْقٍ عِنْدَ مَلِيكٍ مُقْتَدِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ص د ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صِدْق",
        "waznEnglish": "are true",
        "waznTlit": "ṣid'q",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 14,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "صَرْصَرًا",
        "answer": "furious",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 835,
        "tlit": "ṣarṣaran",
        "frequency": 3,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 19,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَرْسَلْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ رِيحًا صَرْصَرًا فِي يَوْمِ نَحْسٍ مُسْتَمِرٍّ",
        "rootWord": "ص ر ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "quadriliteral root",
        "wazn": "ص ر ص ر",
        "waznEnglish": "furious",
        "waznTlit": "ṣād rā ṣād rā",
        "waznType": "Adjective",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "صَغِيرٍ",
        "answer": "small",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 843,
        "tlit": "ṣaghīrin",
        "frequency": 13,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 53,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكُلُّ صَغِيرٍ وَكَبِيرٍ مُسْتَطَرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ص غ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَغِير",
        "waznEnglish": "smaller",
        "waznTlit": "ṣaghīr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "صَيْحَةً",
        "answer": "thunderous blast",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 873,
        "tlit": "ṣayḥatan",
        "frequency": 13,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَرْسَلْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ صَيْحَةً وَاحِدَةً فَكَانُوا كَهَشِيمِ الْمُحْتَظِرِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ي ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ص ي ح",
        "waznEnglish": "the thunderous blast",
        "waznTlit": "ṣād yā ḥā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 13,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "ضَلَالٍ",
        "answer": "error",
        "pcklId": "158",
        "rootWordId": 891,
        "tlit": "ḍalālin",
        "frequency": 191,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 24,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " فَقَالُوا أَبَشَرًا مِنَّا وَاحِدًا نَتَّبِعُهُ إِنَّا إِذًا لَفِي ضَلَالٍ وَسُعُرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ض ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضَلَٰل",
        "waznEnglish": "he went astray (from)",
        "waznTlit": "ḍalāl",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 38,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "ضَلَالٍ",
        "answer": "an error",
        "pcklId": "159",
        "rootWordId": 891,
        "tlit": "ḍalālin",
        "frequency": 191,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 47,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْمُجْرِمِينَ فِي ضَلَالٍ وَسُعُرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ض ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضَلَٰل",
        "waznEnglish": "he went astray (from)",
        "waznTlit": "ḍalāl",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 38,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "ضَيْفِهِ",
        "answer": "his guests",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 901,
        "tlit": "ḍayfihi",
        "frequency": 6,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 37,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ رَاوَدُوهُ عَنْ ضَيْفِهِ فَطَمَسْنَا أَعْيُنَهُمْ",
        "rootWord": "ض ي ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضَيْف",
        "waznEnglish": "offer them hospitality",
        "waznTlit": "ḍayf",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَطَمَسْنَا",
        "answer": "so We blinded",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 924,
        "tlit": "faṭamasnā",
        "frequency": 5,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 37,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ رَاوَدُوهُ عَنْ ضَيْفِهِ فَطَمَسْنَا أَعْيُنَهُمْ فَذُوقُوا عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ط م س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ط م س",
        "waznEnglish": "to blind, to destory, to obliterate",
        "waznTlit": "ṭā mīm sīn",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَبْدَنَا",
        "answer": "Our slave",
        "pcklId": "255",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "ʿabdanā",
        "frequency": 275,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 9,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبَتْ قَبْلَهُمْ قَوْمُ نُوحٍ فَكَذَّبُوا عَبْدَنَا وَقَالُوا مَجْنُونٌ وَازْدُجِرَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبْد",
        "waznEnglish": "we worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabd",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 131,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَعْجَازُ",
        "answer": "trunks",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 960,
        "tlit": "aʿjāzu",
        "frequency": 26,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 20,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " تَنْزِعُ النَّاسَ كَأَنَّهُمْ أَعْجَازُ نَخْلٍ مُنْقَعِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ج ز",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَعْجَاز",
        "waznEnglish": "Am I unable",
        "waznTlit": "aʿjāz",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَذَابِي",
        "answer": "My punishment",
        "pcklId": "323",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "ʿadhābī",
        "frequency": 373,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 16,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَيْفَ كَانَ عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 322,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَذَابِي",
        "answer": "My punishment",
        "pcklId": "324",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "ʿadhābī",
        "frequency": 373,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 18,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبَتْ عَادٌ فَكَيْفَ كَانَ عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 322,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَذَابِي",
        "answer": "My punishment",
        "pcklId": "325",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "ʿadhābī",
        "frequency": 373,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 21,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَيْفَ كَانَ عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 322,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَذَابِي",
        "answer": "My punishment",
        "pcklId": "326",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "ʿadhābī",
        "frequency": 373,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 30,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَيْفَ كَانَ عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 322,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَذَابِي",
        "answer": "My punishment",
        "pcklId": "327",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "ʿadhābī",
        "frequency": 373,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 37,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ رَاوَدُوهُ عَنْ ضَيْفِهِ فَطَمَسْنَا أَعْيُنَهُمْ فَذُوقُوا عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 322,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَذَابٌ",
        "answer": "a punishment",
        "pcklId": "328",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "ʿadhābun",
        "frequency": 373,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 38,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ صَبَّحَهُمْ بُكْرَةً عَذَابٌ مُسْتَقِرٌّ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 322,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَذَابِي",
        "answer": "My punishment",
        "pcklId": "329",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "ʿadhābī",
        "frequency": 373,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 39,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَذُوقُوا عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 322,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يُعْرِضُوا",
        "answer": "they turn away",
        "pcklId": "41",
        "rootWordId": 975,
        "tlit": "yuʿ'riḍū",
        "frequency": 79,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 2,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ يَرَوْا آيَةً يُعْرِضُوا وَيَقُولُوا سِحْرٌ مُسْتَمِرٌّ",
        "rootWord": "ع ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَعْرَضَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to turn away",
        "waznTlit": "aʿraḍa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 32,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَزِيزٍ",
        "answer": "(of) All-Mighty",
        "pcklId": "102",
        "rootWordId": 982,
        "tlit": "ʿazīzin",
        "frequency": 119,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبُوا بِآيَاتِنَا كُلِّهَا فَأَخَذْنَاهُمْ أَخْذَ عَزِيزٍ مُقْتَدِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ز ز",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَزِيز",
        "waznEnglish": "and he overpowered me",
        "waznTlit": "ʿazīz",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 101,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَسِرٌ",
        "answer": "difficult",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 986,
        "tlit": "ʿasirun",
        "frequency": 12,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 8,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " مُهْطِعِينَ إِلَى الدَّاعِ يَقُولُ الْكَافِرُونَ هَٰذَا يَوْمٌ عَسِرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ع س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَسِر",
        "waznEnglish": "you disagree",
        "waznTlit": "ʿasir",
        "waznType": "Adjective",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَتَعَاطَىٰ",
        "answer": "and he took",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1004,
        "tlit": "fataʿāṭā",
        "frequency": 14,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 29,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَنَادَوْا صَاحِبَهُمْ فَتَعَاطَىٰ فَعَقَرَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ط و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَعَاطَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to take",
        "waznTlit": "taʿāṭā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَعَقَرَ",
        "answer": "and hamstrung",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1011,
        "tlit": "faʿaqara",
        "frequency": 8,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 29,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " فَنَادَوْا صَاحِبَهُمْ فَتَعَاطَىٰ فَعَقَرَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ق ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَقَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to hamstrung",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaqara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سَيَعْلَمُونَ",
        "answer": "They will know",
        "pcklId": "336",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "sayaʿlamūna",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " سَيَعْلَمُونَ غَدًا مَنِ الْكَذَّابُ الْأَشِرُ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 382,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عِنْدَ",
        "answer": "near",
        "pcklId": "146",
        "rootWordId": 1028,
        "tlit": "ʿinda",
        "frequency": 201,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 55,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " فِي مَقْعَدِ صِدْقٍ عِنْدَ مَلِيكٍ مُقْتَدِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ن د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِند",
        "waznEnglish": "with",
        "waznTlit": "ʿind",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)",
        "waznFreq": 197,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عِنْدِنَا",
        "answer": "Us",
        "pcklId": "196",
        "rootWordId": 1028,
        "tlit": "ʿindinā",
        "frequency": 201,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 35,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " نِعْمَةً مِنْ عِنْدِنَا كَذَٰلِكَ نَجْزِي مَنْ شَكَرَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ن د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِند",
        "waznEnglish": "with",
        "waznTlit": "ʿind",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 197,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَادٌ",
        "answer": "Aad",
        "pcklId": "56",
        "rootWordId": 1035,
        "tlit": "ʿādun",
        "frequency": 63,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 18,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبَتْ عَادٌ فَكَيْفَ كَانَ عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ع و د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَاد",
        "waznEnglish": "repeated",
        "waznTlit": "ʿād",
        "waznType": "Proper noun",
        "waznFreq": 24,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عُيُونًا",
        "answer": "(with) springs",
        "pcklId": "48",
        "rootWordId": 1046,
        "tlit": "ʿuyūnan",
        "frequency": 65,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 12,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَفَجَّرْنَا الْأَرْضَ عُيُونًا فَالْتَقَى الْمَاءُ عَلَىٰ أَمْرٍ قَدْ قُدِرَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَيْن",
        "waznEnglish": "(having) beautiful eyes",
        "waznTlit": "ʿayn",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 57,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِأَعْيُنِنَا",
        "answer": "before Our eyes",
        "pcklId": "49",
        "rootWordId": 1046,
        "tlit": "bi-aʿyuninā",
        "frequency": 65,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 14,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " تَجْرِي بِأَعْيُنِنَا جَزَاءً لِمَنْ كَانَ كُفِرَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَيْن",
        "waznEnglish": "(having) beautiful eyes",
        "waznTlit": "ʿayn",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 57,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَعْيُنَهُمْ",
        "answer": "their eyes",
        "pcklId": "50",
        "rootWordId": 1046,
        "tlit": "aʿyunahum",
        "frequency": 65,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 37,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ رَاوَدُوهُ عَنْ ضَيْفِهِ فَطَمَسْنَا أَعْيُنَهُمْ",
        "rootWord": "ع ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَيْن",
        "waznEnglish": "(having) beautiful eyes",
        "waznTlit": "ʿayn",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 57,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "غَدًا",
        "answer": "tomorrow",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 1053,
        "tlit": "ghadan",
        "frequency": 16,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " سَيَعْلَمُونَ غَدًا مَنِ الْكَذَّابُ الْأَشِرُ",
        "rootWord": "غ د و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَد",
        "waznEnglish": "you left early morning",
        "waznTlit": "ghad",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَغْلُوبٌ",
        "answer": "one overpowered",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 1073,
        "tlit": "maghlūbun",
        "frequency": 31,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 10,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " فَدَعَا رَبَّهُ أَنِّي مَغْلُوبٌ فَانْتَصِرْ",
        "rootWord": "غ ل ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَغْلُوب",
        "waznEnglish": "overcame",
        "waznTlit": "maghlūb",
        "waznType": "Passive participle",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تُغْنِ",
        "answer": "will avail",
        "pcklId": "36",
        "rootWordId": 1086,
        "tlit": "tugh'ni",
        "frequency": 73,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 5,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " حِكْمَةٌ بَالِغَةٌ فَمَا تُغْنِ النُّذُرُ",
        "rootWord": "غ ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَغْنَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to avail, to enrich",
        "waznTlit": "aghnat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 28,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَفَتَحْنَا",
        "answer": "So We opened",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 1101,
        "tlit": "fafataḥnā",
        "frequency": 38,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 11,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَفَتَحْنَا أَبْوَابَ السَّمَاءِ بِمَاءٍ مُنْهَمِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ف ت ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَتَحَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to open, to give victory",
        "waznTlit": "fataḥa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 16,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فِتْنَةً",
        "answer": "(as) a trial",
        "pcklId": "53",
        "rootWordId": 1105,
        "tlit": "fit'natan",
        "frequency": 60,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 27,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا مُرْسِلُو النَّاقَةِ فِتْنَةً لَهُمْ فَارْتَقِبْهُمْ وَاصْطَبِرْ",
        "rootWord": "ف ت ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فِتْنَة",
        "waznEnglish": "(may) harm you",
        "waznTlit": "fit'nat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 34,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَفَجَّرْنَا",
        "answer": "And We caused to burst",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1108,
        "tlit": "wafajjarnā",
        "frequency": 24,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 12,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَفَجَّرْنَا الْأَرْضَ عُيُونًا فَالْتَقَى الْمَاءُ عَلَىٰ أَمْرٍ قَدْ قُدِرَ",
        "rootWord": "ف ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فُجِّرَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to cause gush",
        "waznTlit": "fujjirat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَعَلُوهُ",
        "answer": "they did",
        "pcklId": "74",
        "rootWordId": 1143,
        "tlit": "faʿalūhu",
        "frequency": 108,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 52,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكُلُّ شَيْءٍ فَعَلُوهُ فِي الزُّبُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ف ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to do",
        "waznTlit": "faʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 88,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَبْلَهُمْ",
        "answer": "before them",
        "pcklId": "269",
        "rootWordId": 1174,
        "tlit": "qablahum",
        "frequency": 294,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 9,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبَتْ قَبْلَهُمْ قَوْمُ نُوحٍ فَكَذَّبُوا عَبْدَنَا وَقَالُوا مَجْنُونٌ وَازْدُجِرَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَبْل",
        "waznEnglish": "will be accepted",
        "waznTlit": "qabl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)",
        "waznFreq": 242,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قُدِرَ",
        "answer": "predestined",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 1181,
        "tlit": "qudira",
        "frequency": 132,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 12,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " وَفَجَّرْنَا الْأَرْضَ عُيُونًا فَالْتَقَى الْمَاءُ عَلَىٰ أَمْرٍ قَدْ قُدِرَ",
        "rootWord": "ق د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَدَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to restrict, to control, to have power",
        "waznTlit": "qadara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 25,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِقَدَرٍ",
        "answer": "by a measure",
        "pcklId": "50",
        "rootWordId": 1181,
        "tlit": "biqadarin",
        "frequency": 132,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 49,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا كُلَّ شَيْءٍ خَلَقْنَاهُ بِقَدَرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَدَر",
        "waznEnglish": "they have control",
        "waznTlit": "qadar",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 11,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُقْتَدِرٍ",
        "answer": "(the) Powerful One",
        "pcklId": "130",
        "rootWordId": 1181,
        "tlit": "muq'tadirin",
        "frequency": 132,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبُوا بِآيَاتِنَا كُلِّهَا فَأَخَذْنَاهُمْ أَخْذَ عَزِيزٍ مُقْتَدِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّقْتَدِر",
        "waznEnglish": "they have control",
        "waznTlit": "muq'tadir",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُقْتَدِرٍ",
        "answer": "Most Powerful",
        "pcklId": "131",
        "rootWordId": 1181,
        "tlit": "muq'tadirin",
        "frequency": 132,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 55,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " فِي مَقْعَدِ صِدْقٍ عِنْدَ مَلِيكٍ مُقْتَدِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّقْتَدِر",
        "waznEnglish": "they have control",
        "waznTlit": "muq'tadir",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْقُرْآنَ",
        "answer": "the Quran",
        "pcklId": "73",
        "rootWordId": 1186,
        "tlit": "l-qur'āna",
        "frequency": 88,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 17,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ يَسَّرْنَا الْقُرْآنَ لِلذِّكْرِ فَهَلْ مِنْ مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قُرْءَان",
        "waznEnglish": "is recited",
        "waznTlit": "qur'ān",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Proper noun)",
        "waznFreq": 70,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْقُرْآنَ",
        "answer": "the Quran",
        "pcklId": "74",
        "rootWordId": 1186,
        "tlit": "l-qur'āna",
        "frequency": 88,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 22,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ يَسَّرْنَا الْقُرْآنَ لِلذِّكْرِ فَهَلْ مِنْ مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قُرْءَان",
        "waznEnglish": "is recited",
        "waznTlit": "qur'ān",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Proper noun)",
        "waznFreq": 70,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْقُرْآنَ",
        "answer": "the Quran",
        "pcklId": "75",
        "rootWordId": 1186,
        "tlit": "l-qur'āna",
        "frequency": 88,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ يَسَّرْنَا الْقُرْآنَ لِلذِّكْرِ فَهَلْ مِنْ مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قُرْءَان",
        "waznEnglish": "is recited",
        "waznTlit": "qur'ān",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Proper noun)",
        "waznFreq": 70,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْقُرْآنَ",
        "answer": "the Quran",
        "pcklId": "76",
        "rootWordId": 1186,
        "tlit": "l-qur'āna",
        "frequency": 88,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 40,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ يَسَّرْنَا الْقُرْآنَ لِلذِّكْرِ فَهَلْ مِنْ مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قُرْءَان",
        "waznEnglish": "is recited",
        "waznTlit": "qur'ān",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Proper noun)",
        "waznFreq": 70,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "اقْتَرَبَتِ",
        "answer": "Has come near",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 1187,
        "tlit": "iq'tarabati",
        "frequency": 96,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 1,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " اقْتَرَبَتِ السَّاعَةُ وَانْشَقَّ الْقَمَرُ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱقْتَرَبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to approach, to go near",
        "waznTlit": "iq'taraba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُسْتَقِرٌّ",
        "answer": "(will be a) settlement",
        "pcklId": "26",
        "rootWordId": 1190,
        "tlit": "mus'taqirrun",
        "frequency": 38,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 3,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَذَّبُوا وَاتَّبَعُوا أَهْوَاءَهُمْ وَكُلُّ أَمْرٍ مُسْتَقِرٌّ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّسْتَقِرّ",
        "waznEnglish": "and cool",
        "waznTlit": "mus'taqirr",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form X)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُسْتَقِرٌّ",
        "answer": "abiding",
        "pcklId": "27",
        "rootWordId": 1190,
        "tlit": "mus'taqirrun",
        "frequency": 38,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 38,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ صَبَّحَهُمْ بُكْرَةً عَذَابٌ مُسْتَقِرٌّ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّسْتَقِرّ",
        "waznEnglish": "and cool",
        "waznTlit": "mus'taqirr",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form X)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قِسْمَةٌ",
        "answer": "(is) to be shared",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 1201,
        "tlit": "qis'matun",
        "frequency": 33,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَبِّئْهُمْ أَنَّ الْمَاءَ قِسْمَةٌ بَيْنَهُمْ كُلُّ شِرْبٍ مُحْتَضَرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق س م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قِسْمَة",
        "waznEnglish": "distribute",
        "waznTlit": "qis'mat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَقْعَدِ",
        "answer": "a seat",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 1218,
        "tlit": "maqʿadi",
        "frequency": 31,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 55,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فِي مَقْعَدِ صِدْقٍ عِنْدَ مَلِيكٍ مُقْتَدِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق ع د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَقْعَد",
        "waznEnglish": "while they sat",
        "waznTlit": "maqʿad",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُنْقَعِرٍ",
        "answer": "uprooted",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1219,
        "tlit": "munqaʿirin",
        "frequency": 1,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 20,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " تَنْزِعُ النَّاسَ كَأَنَّهُمْ أَعْجَازُ نَخْلٍ مُنْقَعِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق ع ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ق ع ر",
        "waznEnglish": "uprooted",
        "waznTlit": "qāf ʿayn rā",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VII)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْقَمَرُ",
        "answer": "the moon",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 1229,
        "tlit": "l-qamaru",
        "frequency": 27,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 1,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " اقْتَرَبَتِ السَّاعَةُ وَانْشَقَّ الْقَمَرُ",
        "rootWord": "ق م ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ق م ر",
        "waznEnglish": "the moon",
        "waznTlit": "qāf mīm rā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 27,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَيَقُولُوا",
        "answer": "and say",
        "pcklId": "1514",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "wayaqūlū",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 2,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ يَرَوْا آيَةً يُعْرِضُوا وَيَقُولُوا سِحْرٌ مُسْتَمِرٌّ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَقُولُ",
        "answer": "Will say",
        "pcklId": "1515",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "yaqūlu",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 8,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " مُهْطِعِينَ إِلَى الدَّاعِ يَقُولُ الْكَافِرُونَ هَٰذَا يَوْمٌ عَسِرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَقَالُوا",
        "answer": "and said",
        "pcklId": "1516",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "waqālū",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 9,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبَتْ قَبْلَهُمْ قَوْمُ نُوحٍ فَكَذَّبُوا عَبْدَنَا وَقَالُوا مَجْنُونٌ وَازْدُجِرَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَقَالُوا",
        "answer": "And said",
        "pcklId": "1517",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "faqālū",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 24,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَقَالُوا أَبَشَرًا مِنَّا وَاحِدًا نَتَّبِعُهُ إِنَّا إِذًا لَفِي ضَلَالٍ وَسُعُرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَقُولُونَ",
        "answer": "(do) they say",
        "pcklId": "1518",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "yaqūlūna",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 44,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ يَقُولُونَ نَحْنُ جَمِيعٌ مُنْتَصِرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَوْمُ",
        "answer": "(the) people",
        "pcklId": "467",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "qawmu",
        "frequency": 660,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 9,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبَتْ قَبْلَهُمْ قَوْمُ نُوحٍ فَكَذَّبُوا عَبْدَنَا وَقَالُوا مَجْنُونٌ وَازْدُجِرَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَوْم",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "qawm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 383,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَوْمُ",
        "answer": "(the) people",
        "pcklId": "468",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "qawmu",
        "frequency": 660,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 33,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبَتْ قَوْمُ لُوطٍ بِالنُّذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَوْم",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "qawm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 383,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَكَبِيرٍ",
        "answer": "and big",
        "pcklId": "137",
        "rootWordId": 1254,
        "tlit": "wakabīrin",
        "frequency": 161,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 53,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكُلُّ صَغِيرٍ وَكَبِيرٍ مُسْتَطَرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ك ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَبِير",
        "waznEnglish": "they will grow up",
        "waznTlit": "kabīr",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 40,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَكَذَّبُوا",
        "answer": "And they denied",
        "pcklId": "123",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "wakadhabū",
        "frequency": 282,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 3,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَذَّبُوا وَاتَّبَعُوا أَهْوَاءَهُمْ وَكُلُّ أَمْرٍ مُسْتَقِرٌّ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deny, to reject",
        "waznTlit": "kadhaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 176,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَذَّبَتْ",
        "answer": "Denied",
        "pcklId": "124",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "kadhabat",
        "frequency": 282,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 9,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبَتْ قَبْلَهُمْ قَوْمُ نُوحٍ فَكَذَّبُوا عَبْدَنَا وَقَالُوا مَجْنُونٌ وَازْدُجِرَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deny, to reject",
        "waznTlit": "kadhaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 176,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَكَذَّبُوا",
        "answer": "and they denied",
        "pcklId": "125",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "fakadhabū",
        "frequency": 282,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 9,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبَتْ قَبْلَهُمْ قَوْمُ نُوحٍ فَكَذَّبُوا عَبْدَنَا وَقَالُوا مَجْنُونٌ وَازْدُجِرَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deny, to reject",
        "waznTlit": "kadhaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 176,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَذَّبَتْ",
        "answer": "Denied",
        "pcklId": "126",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "kadhabat",
        "frequency": 282,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 18,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبَتْ عَادٌ فَكَيْفَ كَانَ عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deny, to reject",
        "waznTlit": "kadhaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 176,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَذَّبَتْ",
        "answer": "Denied",
        "pcklId": "127",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "kadhabat",
        "frequency": 282,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 23,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبَتْ ثَمُودُ بِالنُّذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deny, to reject",
        "waznTlit": "kadhaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 176,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَذَّبَتْ",
        "answer": "Denied",
        "pcklId": "128",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "kadhabat",
        "frequency": 282,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 33,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبَتْ قَوْمُ لُوطٍ بِالنُّذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deny, to reject",
        "waznTlit": "kadhaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 176,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَذَّبُوا",
        "answer": "They denied",
        "pcklId": "129",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "kadhabū",
        "frequency": 282,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبُوا بِآيَاتِنَا كُلِّهَا فَأَخَذْنَاهُمْ أَخْذَ عَزِيزٍ مُقْتَدِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deny, to reject",
        "waznTlit": "kadhaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 176,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَذَّابٌ",
        "answer": "(is) a liar",
        "pcklId": "190",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "kadhābun",
        "frequency": 282,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 25,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " أَأُلْقِيَ الذِّكْرُ عَلَيْهِ مِنْ بَيْنِنَا بَلْ هُوَ كَذَّابٌ أَشِرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّاب",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] lie",
        "waznTlit": "kadhāb",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْكَذَّابُ",
        "answer": "(is) the liar",
        "pcklId": "191",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "l-kadhābu",
        "frequency": 282,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " سَيَعْلَمُونَ غَدًا مَنِ الْكَذَّابُ الْأَشِرُ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّاب",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] lie",
        "waznTlit": "kadhāb",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كُفِرَ",
        "answer": "denied",
        "pcklId": "258",
        "rootWordId": 1280,
        "tlit": "kufira",
        "frequency": 525,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 14,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " تَجْرِي بِأَعْيُنِنَا جَزَاءً لِمَنْ كَانَ كُفِرَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَفَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to disbelieve",
        "waznTlit": "kafara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 289,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَكُفَّارُكُمْ",
        "answer": "Are your disbelievers",
        "pcklId": "320",
        "rootWordId": 1280,
        "tlit": "akuffārukum",
        "frequency": 525,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 43,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " أَكُفَّارُكُمْ خَيْرٌ مِنْ أُولَٰئِكُمْ أَمْ لَكُمْ بَرَاءَةٌ فِي الزُّبُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَافِر",
        "waznEnglish": "disbelieve[d]",
        "waznTlit": "kāfir",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 27,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْكَافِرُونَ",
        "answer": "the disbelievers",
        "pcklId": "500",
        "rootWordId": 1280,
        "tlit": "l-kāfirūna",
        "frequency": 525,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 8,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " مُهْطِعِينَ إِلَى الدَّاعِ يَقُولُ الْكَافِرُونَ هَٰذَا يَوْمٌ عَسِرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ك ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَٰفِرُون",
        "waznEnglish": "disbelieve[d]",
        "waznTlit": "kāfirūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 129,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَكُلُّ",
        "answer": "but (for) every",
        "pcklId": "321",
        "rootWordId": 1288,
        "tlit": "wakullu",
        "frequency": 377,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 3,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَذَّبُوا وَاتَّبَعُوا أَهْوَاءَهُمْ وَكُلُّ أَمْرٍ مُسْتَقِرٌّ",
        "rootWord": "ك ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a burden",
        "waznTlit": "kull",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 359,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كُلُّ",
        "answer": "each",
        "pcklId": "322",
        "rootWordId": 1288,
        "tlit": "kullu",
        "frequency": 377,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَبِّئْهُمْ أَنَّ الْمَاءَ قِسْمَةٌ بَيْنَهُمْ كُلُّ شِرْبٍ مُحْتَضَرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ك ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a burden",
        "waznTlit": "kull",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 359,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كُلِّهَا",
        "answer": "all of them",
        "pcklId": "323",
        "rootWordId": 1288,
        "tlit": "kullihā",
        "frequency": 377,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبُوا بِآيَاتِنَا كُلِّهَا فَأَخَذْنَاهُمْ أَخْذَ عَزِيزٍ مُقْتَدِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a burden",
        "waznTlit": "kull",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 359,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كُلَّ",
        "answer": "every",
        "pcklId": "324",
        "rootWordId": 1288,
        "tlit": "kulla",
        "frequency": 377,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 49,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا كُلَّ شَيْءٍ خَلَقْنَاهُ بِقَدَرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a burden",
        "waznTlit": "kull",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 359,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَكُلُّ",
        "answer": "And every",
        "pcklId": "325",
        "rootWordId": 1288,
        "tlit": "wakullu",
        "frequency": 377,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 52,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكُلُّ شَيْءٍ فَعَلُوهُ فِي الزُّبُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a burden",
        "waznTlit": "kull",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 359,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَكُلُّ",
        "answer": "And every",
        "pcklId": "326",
        "rootWordId": 1288,
        "tlit": "wakullu",
        "frequency": 377,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 53,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكُلُّ صَغِيرٍ وَكَبِيرٍ مُسْتَطَرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ك ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a burden",
        "waznTlit": "kull",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 359,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانَ",
        "answer": "was",
        "pcklId": "1238",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kāna",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 14,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " تَجْرِي بِأَعْيُنِنَا جَزَاءً لِمَنْ كَانَ كُفِرَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانَ",
        "answer": "was",
        "pcklId": "1239",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kāna",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 16,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَيْفَ كَانَ عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانَ",
        "answer": "was",
        "pcklId": "1240",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kāna",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 18,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبَتْ عَادٌ فَكَيْفَ كَانَ عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانَ",
        "answer": "was",
        "pcklId": "1241",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kāna",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 21,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَيْفَ كَانَ عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانَ",
        "answer": "was",
        "pcklId": "1242",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kāna",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 30,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَيْفَ كَانَ عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَكَانُوا",
        "answer": "and they became",
        "pcklId": "1243",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "fakānū",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَرْسَلْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ صَيْحَةً وَاحِدَةً فَكَانُوا كَهَشِيمِ الْمُحْتَظِرِ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَكَيْفَ",
        "answer": "So how",
        "pcklId": "63",
        "rootWordId": 1308,
        "tlit": "fakayfa",
        "frequency": 83,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 16,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَيْفَ كَانَ عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ي ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك ي ف",
        "waznEnglish": "How",
        "waznTlit": "kāf yā fā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Interogative particle)",
        "waznFreq": 83,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَكَيْفَ",
        "answer": "so how",
        "pcklId": "64",
        "rootWordId": 1308,
        "tlit": "fakayfa",
        "frequency": 83,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 18,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبَتْ عَادٌ فَكَيْفَ كَانَ عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ي ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك ي ف",
        "waznEnglish": "How",
        "waznTlit": "kāf yā fā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Interogative particle)",
        "waznFreq": 83,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَكَيْفَ",
        "answer": "So how",
        "pcklId": "65",
        "rootWordId": 1308,
        "tlit": "fakayfa",
        "frequency": 83,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 21,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَيْفَ كَانَ عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ي ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك ي ف",
        "waznEnglish": "How",
        "waznTlit": "kāf yā fā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Interogative particle)",
        "waznFreq": 83,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَكَيْفَ",
        "answer": "So how",
        "pcklId": "66",
        "rootWordId": 1308,
        "tlit": "fakayfa",
        "frequency": 83,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 30,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَيْفَ كَانَ عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ي ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك ي ف",
        "waznEnglish": "How",
        "waznTlit": "kāf yā fā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Interogative particle)",
        "waznFreq": 83,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَأُلْقِيَ",
        "answer": "Has been sent",
        "pcklId": "87",
        "rootWordId": 1347,
        "tlit": "a-ul'qiya",
        "frequency": 146,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 25,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " أَأُلْقِيَ الذِّكْرُ عَلَيْهِ مِنْ بَيْنِنَا بَلْ هُوَ كَذَّابٌ أَشِرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ل ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَلْقَىٰٓ",
        "waznEnglish": "to cast, to throw, to meet, to offer",
        "waznTlit": "alqā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 71,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَالْتَقَى",
        "answer": "so met",
        "pcklId": "103",
        "rootWordId": 1347,
        "tlit": "fal-taqā",
        "frequency": 146,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 12,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَفَجَّرْنَا الْأَرْضَ عُيُونًا فَالْتَقَى الْمَاءُ عَلَىٰ أَمْرٍ قَدْ قُدِرَ",
        "rootWord": "ل ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱلْتَقَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to meet",
        "waznTlit": "al'taqā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 7,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَلَمْحٍ",
        "answer": "like the twinkling",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1348,
        "tlit": "kalamḥin",
        "frequency": 2,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 50,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا أَمْرُنَا إِلَّا وَاحِدَةٌ كَلَمْحٍ بِالْبَصَرِ",
        "rootWord": "ل م ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ل م ح",
        "waznEnglish": "as a twinkling",
        "waznTlit": "lām mīm ḥā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَلْوَاحٍ",
        "answer": "(ark) made of planks",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 1357,
        "tlit": "alwāḥin",
        "frequency": 6,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 13,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَحَمَلْنَاهُ عَلَىٰ ذَاتِ أَلْوَاحٍ وَدُسُرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ل و ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لَوْح",
        "waznEnglish": "Scorching",
        "waznTlit": "lawḥ",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَمَرُّ",
        "answer": "and more bitter",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 1385,
        "tlit": "wa-amarru",
        "frequency": 35,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 46,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " بَلِ السَّاعَةُ مَوْعِدُهُمْ وَالسَّاعَةُ أَدْهَىٰ وَأَمَرُّ",
        "rootWord": "م ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمَرّ",
        "waznEnglish": "passed",
        "waznTlit": "amarr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُسْتَمِرٌّ",
        "answer": "continuing",
        "pcklId": "33",
        "rootWordId": 1385,
        "tlit": "mus'tamirrun",
        "frequency": 35,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 2,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ يَرَوْا آيَةً يُعْرِضُوا وَيَقُولُوا سِحْرٌ مُسْتَمِرٌّ",
        "rootWord": "م ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّسْتَمِرّ",
        "waznEnglish": "passed",
        "waznTlit": "mus'tamirr",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form X)",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُسْتَمِرٍّ",
        "answer": "continuous",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 1385,
        "tlit": "mus'tamirrin",
        "frequency": 35,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 19,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَرْسَلْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ رِيحًا صَرْصَرًا فِي يَوْمِ نَحْسٍ مُسْتَمِرٍّ",
        "rootWord": "م ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّسْتَمِرّ",
        "waznEnglish": "passed",
        "waznTlit": "mus'tamirr",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form X)",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَتَمَارَوْا",
        "answer": "but they disputed",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1387,
        "tlit": "fatamāraw",
        "frequency": 20,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 36,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ أَنْذَرَهُمْ بَطْشَتَنَا فَتَمَارَوْا بِالنُّذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "م ر ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَمَارَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to dispute, to doubt",
        "waznTlit": "tamāra",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَسَّ",
        "answer": "(the) touch",
        "pcklId": "59",
        "rootWordId": 1394,
        "tlit": "massa",
        "frequency": 61,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 48,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يُسْحَبُونَ فِي النَّارِ عَلَىٰ وُجُوهِهِمْ ذُوقُوا مَسَّ سَقَرَ",
        "rootWord": "م س س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَسّ",
        "waznEnglish": "will touch us",
        "waznTlit": "mass",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَلِيكٍ",
        "answer": "a King",
        "pcklId": "201",
        "rootWordId": 1415,
        "tlit": "malīkin",
        "frequency": 206,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 55,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " فِي مَقْعَدِ صِدْقٍ عِنْدَ مَلِيكٍ مُقْتَدِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "م ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَلِيك",
        "waznEnglish": "possesses",
        "waznTlit": "malīk",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِمَاءٍ",
        "answer": "with water",
        "pcklId": "48",
        "rootWordId": 1428,
        "tlit": "bimāin",
        "frequency": 63,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 11,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " فَفَتَحْنَا أَبْوَابَ السَّمَاءِ بِمَاءٍ مُنْهَمِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "م و ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م و ه",
        "waznEnglish": "water",
        "waznTlit": "mīm wāw hā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 63,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَاءُ",
        "answer": "the water(s)",
        "pcklId": "49",
        "rootWordId": 1428,
        "tlit": "l-māu",
        "frequency": 63,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 12,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَفَجَّرْنَا الْأَرْضَ عُيُونًا فَالْتَقَى الْمَاءُ عَلَىٰ أَمْرٍ قَدْ قُدِرَ",
        "rootWord": "م و ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م و ه",
        "waznEnglish": "water",
        "waznTlit": "mīm wāw hā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 63,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَاءَ",
        "answer": "the water",
        "pcklId": "50",
        "rootWordId": 1428,
        "tlit": "l-māa",
        "frequency": 63,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَبِّئْهُمْ أَنَّ الْمَاءَ قِسْمَةٌ بَيْنَهُمْ كُلُّ شِرْبٍ مُحْتَضَرٌ",
        "rootWord": "م و ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م و ه",
        "waznEnglish": "water",
        "waznTlit": "mīm wāw hā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 63,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنَبِّئْهُمْ",
        "answer": "And inform them",
        "pcklId": "37",
        "rootWordId": 1434,
        "tlit": "wanabbi'hum",
        "frequency": 160,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَبِّئْهُمْ أَنَّ الْمَاءَ قِسْمَةٌ بَيْنَهُمْ كُلُّ شِرْبٍ مُحْتَضَرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ن ب أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَبَّأَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to inform",
        "waznTlit": "nabba-a",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 46,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَنْبَاءِ",
        "answer": "the information",
        "pcklId": "77",
        "rootWordId": 1434,
        "tlit": "l-anbāi",
        "frequency": 160,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 4,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ جَاءَهُمْ مِنَ الْأَنْبَاءِ مَا فِيهِ مُزْدَجَرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ن ب أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَبَأ",
        "waznEnglish": "Shall I inform you",
        "waznTlit": "naba",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 29,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نَجَّيْنَاهُمْ",
        "answer": "We saved them",
        "pcklId": "36",
        "rootWordId": 1445,
        "tlit": "najjaynāhum",
        "frequency": 84,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 34,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَرْسَلْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ حَاصِبًا إِلَّا آلَ لُوطٍ نَجَّيْنَاهُمْ بِسَحَرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ن ج و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَجَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to save, to deliver",
        "waznTlit": "najjā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 37,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نَحْسٍ",
        "answer": "(of) misfortune",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1449,
        "tlit": "naḥsin",
        "frequency": 3,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 19,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَرْسَلْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ رِيحًا صَرْصَرًا فِي يَوْمِ نَحْسٍ مُسْتَمِرٍّ",
        "rootWord": "ن ح س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَحْس",
        "waznEnglish": "and smoke",
        "waznTlit": "naḥs",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نَخْلٍ",
        "answer": "(of) date-palms",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 1452,
        "tlit": "nakhlin",
        "frequency": 20,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 20,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " تَنْزِعُ النَّاسَ كَأَنَّهُمْ أَعْجَازُ نَخْلٍ مُنْقَعِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ن خ ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَخْل",
        "waznEnglish": "the date-palm",
        "waznTlit": "nakhl",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 11,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَنَادَوْا",
        "answer": "But they called",
        "pcklId": "39",
        "rootWordId": 1455,
        "tlit": "fanādaw",
        "frequency": 53,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 29,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَنَادَوْا صَاحِبَهُمْ فَتَعَاطَىٰ فَعَقَرَ",
        "rootWord": "ن د و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَادَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to call",
        "waznTlit": "nādā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form III)",
        "waznFreq": 44,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَنْذَرَهُمْ",
        "answer": "he warned them",
        "pcklId": "43",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "andharahum",
        "frequency": 130,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 36,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ أَنْذَرَهُمْ بَطْشَتَنَا فَتَمَارَوْا بِالنُّذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَنذَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to warn",
        "waznTlit": "andhara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 44,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "النُّذُرُ",
        "answer": "the warnings",
        "pcklId": "93",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "l-nudhuru",
        "frequency": 130,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 5,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " حِكْمَةٌ بَالِغَةٌ فَمَا تُغْنِ النُّذُرُ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَذِير",
        "waznEnglish": "you vow",
        "waznTlit": "nadhīr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 58,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنُذُرِ",
        "answer": "and My warnings",
        "pcklId": "94",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "wanudhuri",
        "frequency": 130,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 16,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَيْفَ كَانَ عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَذِير",
        "waznEnglish": "you vow",
        "waznTlit": "nadhīr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 58,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنُذُرِ",
        "answer": "and My warnings",
        "pcklId": "95",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "wanudhuri",
        "frequency": 130,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 18,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبَتْ عَادٌ فَكَيْفَ كَانَ عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَذِير",
        "waznEnglish": "you vow",
        "waznTlit": "nadhīr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 58,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنُذُرِ",
        "answer": "and My warnings",
        "pcklId": "96",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "wanudhuri",
        "frequency": 130,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 21,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَيْفَ كَانَ عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَذِير",
        "waznEnglish": "you vow",
        "waznTlit": "nadhīr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 58,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالنُّذُرِ",
        "answer": "the warnings",
        "pcklId": "97",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "bil-nudhuri",
        "frequency": 130,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 23,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبَتْ ثَمُودُ بِالنُّذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَذِير",
        "waznEnglish": "you vow",
        "waznTlit": "nadhīr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 58,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنُذُرِ",
        "answer": "and My warnings",
        "pcklId": "98",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "wanudhuri",
        "frequency": 130,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 30,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَيْفَ كَانَ عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَذِير",
        "waznEnglish": "you vow",
        "waznTlit": "nadhīr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 58,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالنُّذُرِ",
        "answer": "the warnings",
        "pcklId": "99",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "bil-nudhuri",
        "frequency": 130,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 33,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَّبَتْ قَوْمُ لُوطٍ بِالنُّذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَذِير",
        "waznEnglish": "you vow",
        "waznTlit": "nadhīr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 58,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالنُّذُرِ",
        "answer": "the warnings",
        "pcklId": "100",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "bil-nudhuri",
        "frequency": 130,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 36,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ أَنْذَرَهُمْ بَطْشَتَنَا فَتَمَارَوْا بِالنُّذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَذِير",
        "waznEnglish": "you vow",
        "waznTlit": "nadhīr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 58,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنُذُرِ",
        "answer": "and My warnings",
        "pcklId": "101",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "wanudhuri",
        "frequency": 130,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 37,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ رَاوَدُوهُ عَنْ ضَيْفِهِ فَطَمَسْنَا أَعْيُنَهُمْ فَذُوقُوا عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَذِير",
        "waznEnglish": "you vow",
        "waznTlit": "nadhīr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 58,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنُذُرِ",
        "answer": "and My warnings",
        "pcklId": "102",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "wanudhuri",
        "frequency": 130,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 39,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَذُوقُوا عَذَابِي وَنُذُرِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَذِير",
        "waznEnglish": "you vow",
        "waznTlit": "nadhīr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 58,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "النُّذُرُ",
        "answer": "warnings",
        "pcklId": "103",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "l-nudhuru",
        "frequency": 130,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 41,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ جَاءَ آلَ فِرْعَوْنَ النُّذُرُ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَذِير",
        "waznEnglish": "you vow",
        "waznTlit": "nadhīr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 58,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَنْزِعُ",
        "answer": "Plucking out",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 1457,
        "tlit": "tanziʿu",
        "frequency": 20,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 20,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " تَنْزِعُ النَّاسَ كَأَنَّهُمْ أَعْجَازُ نَخْلٍ مُنْقَعِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَزَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to take way, to remove, to withdraw",
        "waznTlit": "nazaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 10,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُنْتَشِرٌ",
        "answer": "spreading",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 1471,
        "tlit": "muntashirun",
        "frequency": 21,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " يَخْرُجُونَ مِنَ الْأَجْدَاثِ كَأَنَّهُمْ جَرَادٌ مُنْتَشِرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ن ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّنتَشِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Will spread",
        "waznTlit": "muntashir",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَانْتَصِرْ",
        "answer": "so help",
        "pcklId": "65",
        "rootWordId": 1477,
        "tlit": "fa-intaṣir",
        "frequency": 158,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 10,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " فَدَعَا رَبَّهُ أَنِّي مَغْلُوبٌ فَانْتَصِرْ",
        "rootWord": "ن ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱنتَصَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to defend, to help",
        "waznTlit": "intaṣara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 7,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُنْتَصِرٌ",
        "answer": "helping (each other)",
        "pcklId": "157",
        "rootWordId": 1477,
        "tlit": "muntaṣirun",
        "frequency": 158,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 44,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ يَقُولُونَ نَحْنُ جَمِيعٌ مُنْتَصِرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ن ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّنتَصِر",
        "waznEnglish": "will be helped",
        "waznTlit": "muntaṣir",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نِعْمَةً",
        "answer": "(As) a favor",
        "pcklId": "115",
        "rootWordId": 1492,
        "tlit": "niʿ'matan",
        "frequency": 140,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 35,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " نِعْمَةً مِنْ عِنْدِنَا كَذَٰلِكَ نَجْزِي مَنْ شَكَرَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ع م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نِعْمَة",
        "waznEnglish": "then good",
        "waznTlit": "niʿ'mat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 50,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نُكُرٍ",
        "answer": "terrible",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 1517,
        "tlit": "nukurin",
        "frequency": 37,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 6,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " فَتَوَلَّ عَنْهُمْ يَوْمَ يَدْعُ الدَّاعِ إِلَىٰ شَيْءٍ نُكُرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ن ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نُّكُر",
        "waznEnglish": "he felt unfamiliar of them",
        "waznTlit": "nukur",
        "waznType": "Adjective",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنَهَرٍ",
        "answer": "and river",
        "pcklId": "103",
        "rootWordId": 1525,
        "tlit": "wanaharin",
        "frequency": 113,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 54,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْمُتَّقِينَ فِي جَنَّاتٍ وَنَهَرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ن ه ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَهَر",
        "waznEnglish": "repel them",
        "waznTlit": "nahar",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 54,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "النَّارِ",
        "answer": "the Fire",
        "pcklId": "121",
        "rootWordId": 1529,
        "tlit": "l-nāri",
        "frequency": 194,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 48,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يُسْحَبُونَ فِي النَّارِ عَلَىٰ وُجُوهِهِمْ ذُوقُوا مَسَّ سَقَرَ",
        "rootWord": "ن و ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَار",
        "waznEnglish": "a fire",
        "waznTlit": "nār",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 145,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "النَّاسَ",
        "answer": "men",
        "pcklId": "224",
        "rootWordId": 1530,
        "tlit": "l-nāsa",
        "frequency": 241,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 20,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " تَنْزِعُ النَّاسَ كَأَنَّهُمْ أَعْجَازُ نَخْلٍ مُنْقَعِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ن و س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ن و س",
        "waznEnglish": "the people",
        "waznTlit": "nūn wāw sīn",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 241,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "النَّاقَةِ",
        "answer": "the she-camel",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1533,
        "tlit": "l-nāqati",
        "frequency": 7,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 27,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا مُرْسِلُو النَّاقَةِ فِتْنَةً لَهُمْ فَارْتَقِبْهُمْ وَاصْطَبِرْ",
        "rootWord": "ن و ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ن و ق",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a she-camel",
        "waznTlit": "nūn wāw qāf",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 7,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سَيُهْزَمُ",
        "answer": "Soon will be defeated",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1553,
        "tlit": "sayuh'zamu",
        "frequency": 3,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 45,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " سَيُهْزَمُ الْجَمْعُ وَيُوَلُّونَ الدُّبُرَ",
        "rootWord": "ه ز م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "هَزَمُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to defeat",
        "waznTlit": "hazamu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَهَشِيمِ",
        "answer": "like dry twig fragments",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1555,
        "tlit": "kahashīmi",
        "frequency": 2,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَرْسَلْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ صَيْحَةً وَاحِدَةً فَكَانُوا كَهَشِيمِ الْمُحْتَظِرِ",
        "rootWord": "ه ش م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ه ش م",
        "waznEnglish": "dry stalks",
        "waznTlit": "hā shīn mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُهْطِعِينَ",
        "answer": "Racing ahead",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1557,
        "tlit": "muh'ṭiʿīna",
        "frequency": 3,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 8,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " مُهْطِعِينَ إِلَى الدَّاعِ يَقُولُ الْكَافِرُونَ هَٰذَا يَوْمٌ عَسِرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ه ط ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ه ط ع",
        "waznEnglish": "Racing ahead",
        "waznTlit": "hā ṭā ʿayn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَهْلَكْنَا",
        "answer": "We destroyed",
        "pcklId": "50",
        "rootWordId": 1559,
        "tlit": "ahlaknā",
        "frequency": 68,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 51,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ أَهْلَكْنَا أَشْيَاعَكُمْ فَهَلْ مِنْ مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ه ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَهْلَكَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to destroy",
        "waznTlit": "ahlaka",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 51,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُنْهَمِرٍ",
        "answer": "pouring down",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1562,
        "tlit": "mun'hamirin",
        "frequency": 1,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 11,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " فَفَتَحْنَا أَبْوَابَ السَّمَاءِ بِمَاءٍ مُنْهَمِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ه م ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ه م ر",
        "waznEnglish": "pouring down",
        "waznTlit": "hā mīm rā",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VII)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَهْوَاءَهُمْ",
        "answer": "their desires",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 1571,
        "tlit": "ahwāahum",
        "frequency": 38,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 3,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَذَّبُوا وَاتَّبَعُوا أَهْوَاءَهُمْ وَكُلُّ أَمْرٍ مُسْتَقِرٌّ",
        "rootWord": "ه و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَهْوَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "desire",
        "waznTlit": "ahwā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 17,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وُجُوهِهِمْ",
        "answer": "their faces",
        "pcklId": "61",
        "rootWordId": 1592,
        "tlit": "wujūhihim",
        "frequency": 78,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 48,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يُسْحَبُونَ فِي النَّارِ عَلَىٰ وُجُوهِهِمْ ذُوقُوا مَسَّ سَقَرَ",
        "rootWord": "و ج ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَجْه",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] have turned",
        "waznTlit": "wajh",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 72,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاحِدًا",
        "answer": "one",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 1593,
        "tlit": "wāḥidan",
        "frequency": 68,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 24,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " فَقَالُوا أَبَشَرًا مِنَّا وَاحِدًا نَتَّبِعُهُ إِنَّا إِذًا لَفِي ضَلَالٍ وَسُعُرٍ",
        "rootWord": "و ح د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَٰحِد",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) one (kind)",
        "waznTlit": "wāḥid",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 30,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاحِدَةً",
        "answer": "single",
        "pcklId": "50",
        "rootWordId": 1593,
        "tlit": "wāḥidatan",
        "frequency": 68,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَرْسَلْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ صَيْحَةً وَاحِدَةً فَكَانُوا كَهَشِيمِ الْمُحْتَظِرِ",
        "rootWord": "و ح د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَٰحِدَة",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) one (kind)",
        "waznTlit": "wāḥidat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 31,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاحِدَةٌ",
        "answer": "one",
        "pcklId": "51",
        "rootWordId": 1593,
        "tlit": "wāḥidatun",
        "frequency": 68,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 50,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا أَمْرُنَا إِلَّا وَاحِدَةٌ كَلَمْحٍ بِالْبَصَرِ",
        "rootWord": "و ح د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَٰحِدَة",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) one (kind)",
        "waznTlit": "wāḥidat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 31,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَوْعِدُهُمْ",
        "answer": "(is) their promised time",
        "pcklId": "87",
        "rootWordId": 1626,
        "tlit": "mawʿiduhum",
        "frequency": 151,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 46,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " بَلِ السَّاعَةُ مَوْعِدُهُمْ وَالسَّاعَةُ أَدْهَىٰ وَأَمَرُّ",
        "rootWord": "و ع د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّوْعِد",
        "waznEnglish": "promises you",
        "waznTlit": "mawʿid",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 12,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُتَّقِينَ",
        "answer": "the righteous",
        "pcklId": "253",
        "rootWordId": 1641,
        "tlit": "l-mutaqīna",
        "frequency": 258,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 54,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْمُتَّقِينَ فِي جَنَّاتٍ وَنَهَرٍ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُتَّقِين",
        "waznEnglish": "and save us",
        "waznTlit": "muttaqīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 49,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَيُوَلُّونَ",
        "answer": "and they will turn",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 1648,
        "tlit": "wayuwallūna",
        "frequency": 232,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 45,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " سَيُهْزَمُ الْجَمْعُ وَيُوَلُّونَ الدُّبُرَ",
        "rootWord": "و ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَلَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to turn",
        "waznTlit": "wallā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 30,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَتَوَلَّ",
        "answer": "So turn away",
        "pcklId": "94",
        "rootWordId": 1648,
        "tlit": "fatawalla",
        "frequency": 232,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 6,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَتَوَلَّ عَنْهُمْ يَوْمَ يَدْعُ الدَّاعِ إِلَىٰ شَيْءٍ نُكُرٍ",
        "rootWord": "و ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَوَلَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to turn",
        "waznTlit": "tawallā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)",
        "waznFreq": 78,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسَّرْنَا",
        "answer": "We have made easy",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1658,
        "tlit": "yassarnā",
        "frequency": 44,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 17,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ يَسَّرْنَا الْقُرْآنَ لِلذِّكْرِ فَهَلْ مِنْ مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ي س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَسَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make easy",
        "waznTlit": "yassara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 11,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسَّرْنَا",
        "answer": "We have made easy",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 1658,
        "tlit": "yassarnā",
        "frequency": 44,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 22,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ يَسَّرْنَا الْقُرْآنَ لِلذِّكْرِ فَهَلْ مِنْ مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ي س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَسَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make easy",
        "waznTlit": "yassara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 11,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسَّرْنَا",
        "answer": "We have made easy",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1658,
        "tlit": "yassarnā",
        "frequency": 44,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ يَسَّرْنَا الْقُرْآنَ لِلذِّكْرِ فَهَلْ مِنْ مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ي س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَسَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make easy",
        "waznTlit": "yassara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 11,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسَّرْنَا",
        "answer": "We have made easy",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 1658,
        "tlit": "yassarnā",
        "frequency": 44,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 40,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ يَسَّرْنَا الْقُرْآنَ لِلذِّكْرِ فَهَلْ مِنْ مُدَّكِرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ي س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَسَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make easy",
        "waznTlit": "yassara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 11,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمٌ",
        "answer": "(is) a Day",
        "pcklId": "273",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawmun",
        "frequency": 405,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 8,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " مُهْطِعِينَ إِلَى الدَّاعِ يَقُولُ الْكَافِرُونَ هَٰذَا يَوْمٌ عَسِرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 405,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمِ",
        "answer": "a day",
        "pcklId": "274",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawmi",
        "frequency": 405,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 19,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَرْسَلْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ رِيحًا صَرْصَرًا فِي يَوْمِ نَحْسٍ مُسْتَمِرٍّ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 405,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(The) Day",
        "pcklId": "275",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawma",
        "frequency": 405,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 48,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يُسْحَبُونَ فِي النَّارِ عَلَىٰ وُجُوهِهِمْ ذُوقُوا مَسَّ سَقَرَ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 405,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(The) Day",
        "pcklId": "384",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawma",
        "frequency": 405,
        "surahnum": 54,
        "ayahnum": 6,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَتَوَلَّ عَنْهُمْ يَوْمَ يَدْعُ الدَّاعِ إِلَىٰ شَيْءٍ نُكُرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)",
        "waznFreq": 405,
        "hasRootWord": true
    }
]; 
export default words;